I did an internship in China once in
Chengdu. They had a napping room, like a
room where you could go and lie down on
the sofa. And I was explicitly told,
"This is where you can lie down in the
afternoon." And I was like, "Is that
serious? Because I will definitely use
that opportunity, but I don't want you
to think that I'm lazy." I did have a
nap once or twice, but I felt really bad
about it. And I was like, "Oh my god,
everyone knows that I'm napping. This is
so bad." Because in the UK we do not
nap, right?
>> No, absolutely not. You could get in
trouble for doing that. I think people
would assume that you're ill, you
haven't slept enough the night before,
like what are you doing? You're just not
conducting yourself properly. Like yeah,
sleeping at your desk is just like no.
What are you What are you doing?
>> this about our culture. You know, like
in East Asia, they usually at lunchtime,
from very young. Obviously, in the UK,
young children have nap time. But once
you start primary school, that's not a
thing anymore. But they still have this
ritual of like a 20-30 minute, put your
head down on your desk after [music]
lunch. I think even up into secondary
school. And then at work, you can do the
same thing. But I think it's so good
because there is that dip in your
circadian rhythm, and you need that
rest. And for me, it's so clear, there's
no point in me doing any work because I
just have to switch off briefly. But
there's no way you can go and do that,
and it's really annoying.
>> Yeah, I think it makes sense. Like yeah,
especially after lunch. Yeah, it it
would it hurt to have just half an hour
or even an hour? If you stay the extra
time, you know?
>> come back fresh.
>> Exactly.
>> New ideas, new energy.
>> In Spain, it's always been very popular,
the siesta, where they have a sort of
break in the afternoon and like a little
nap maybe. So, yeah, I don't know why we
just persist [music] with it.